# **Résumé**

# ABDALLATIF ABDALRHMAN

#### Address:

6-035, Markin/CNRL Natural Resources Engineering Facility University of Alberta Edmonton (T6G 2W2), Alberta, Canada.

#### **Personal Profile:**

A motivated, adaptable and creative environmental engineer equipped with solid skills, diverse experience and global vision. I have worked in four different continents which allowed me to develop precious technical, organisational and multi-cultural communication skills.

# **Experience:**

• September 2014 - Now

**Research Assistant (Oil Sands Tailings Remediation)**, Future Energy Systems / Dept. of Civil & Environmental Engineering, University of Alberta, *Canada*.

• <u>June - September 2018</u>

**R&D Intern**, Innovation Management - Fuel & Lubricant Solutions, BASF SE, *Germany*.

May- August 2014

Chemical Process Engineer, Fuchs Lubricants & Greases, Sudan.

• May - August 2013

Intern, Research & Innovation Division, Veolia Environment, China.

• <u>September 2010 - July 2011</u>

Production Engineer, Fuchs Lubricants & Greases - Sudan.

### **Skills**

# **Environmental Engineering skills**

- Water/wastewater process design
- Air quality assessment
- Environmental site assessment / Soil remediation

## **Computer skills**

- Simulation & Design: WatPro, BioWin, ChemiCAD, Aspen HYSYS, AutoCAD
- Statistical analysis software: JMP
- Microsoft office: Word, Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint...etc.

#### **Languages**

- English (Fluent)
- Arabic (Fluent)
- Chinese Mandarin (Listening & Speaking Limited proficiency)
- German (Beginner)

#### **Education:**

- PhD Civil & Environmental Engineering (Expected April 2019) <u>Excellent</u> (University of Alberta, Canada)
- M.Sc. Environmental Engineering (Dec. 2013) <u>Excellent</u> (Tsinghua University, China)
- B.Sc. (Honours) Chemical Engineering (Aug. 2009) First class (University of Khartoum, Sudan)

### **Honors & Awards**

- Canadian Oil Sands Network for Research and Development (CONRAD) Scholarship, 2019
- Petro-Canada Graduate Scholarship in Petroleum Engineering Canada, 2018
- DAAD-RISE Professional Scholarship Germany, 2018
- Mary Louise Imrie Graduate Student Award Canada, 2018
- Graduate Student Association (GSA) Travel Award Canada, 2018
- NSERC -CRATE (Collaborative Research and Training Experience) Canada, 2017
- Shell Enhanced Learning Fund Award Canada, 2017
- Graduate Student Association (GSA) Travel Award Canada, 2017
- Dr. Donald R Stanley Scholarship in Environmental (Civil) Engineering Canada, 2016
- University of Alberta Doctoral Recruitment Scholarship Canada, 2014
- CSC Full merit-based master scholarship (Chinese Ministry of Education), 2011-2013
- (Tsinghua- Guanghua) Excellence Award China, 2012

## **Professional Memberships**

The Association of Professional Engineers and Geoscientists of Alberta (APEGA)
Engineer-in-Training (EIT)

## **Leadership Roles**

- President Sudanese Canadian Youth Association in Edmonton 2015-2017
- Vice President African Students Association in Beijing, China 2012 2013
- Vice President Engineering Society, University of Khartoum 2007-2009
- Captain Faculty of Engineering Soccer Team, University of Khartoum 2006-2007

#### Volunteer

- April 2018 Science Mentor Mount Pleasant School.
- April 2017 Earth Day Celebration for Syrian refugees: MAC Center, Edmonton.
- 2017 **Student Sustainability Service** University of Alberta, Edmonton.
- February 2016 Family Science Night in **Mount Pleasant School**.
- December 2015 Science Demo for students Westmount public school, Edmonton
- September 2015 April 2016: **University of Alberta Student Sustainability Service.**
- July 2015: Water for People Fundraiser Western Canada Water Association, Edmonton.